Faisal Ahmed

Google Certified Associate Android Developer



- House -210, Road -2, Avenue-3, Mirpur DOHS.
- ≥ imdevfaisal@gmail.com
- **** 01763297075
- Github

SUMMARY

With over 7 years of experience in the mobile application development industry, I have specialized in creating both native Android and Flutter-based mobile applications. My responsibilities the encompass entire development lifecycle, from initial requirement analysis to design, development, and unit testing. My extensive background in these areas enables me to produce highquality, efficient mobile solutions tailored to meet specific client needs.

AWARDS

National Hackathon 2014

ICT Division

06/12/2014

Runners up on Corruption Category (https://www.nationalappsbd.com/?page_id=2013)

Employee of the month

W 3Engineers Ltd

EDUCATION

Bachelor of computer science and engineering

IUBAT ☑

2012 – 2016 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cheq Inc. 🛮

Sr. Flutter Engineer

11/2022 – present | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Developed architectural solutions, ensuring robust and streamlined designs.
- Coordinated code reviews, enhancing performance and clarity.
- Steered **POS terminal** operations for uninterrupted service.
- Coordinated the debut of pivotal features, aligning with core objectives and superior quality.

Highlighted Achievements:

- Transitioned from legacy code, modernizing with up-to-date Flutter and Dart versions.
- Addressed critical Sentry issues, amplifying sales during peak stadium events.
- Overcame dual screen crash challenges, elevating vendor satisfaction.
- Implemented TDD Architecture, Strengthening code reliability.
- Added UI test Patrol.
- Innovated a handheld POS application, boosting sales by **30%**.

Audacity IT Solutions LTD 🛭

Sr. Flutter Engineer

11/2021 - 11/2022 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities/Tasks:

During my tenure at **Audacity IT Solutions LTD**, I was instrumental in developing and maintaining large-scale Flutter applications. My key responsibilities included:

Architecting Projects: Creating the structural design for various applications, ensuring robustness and scalability. Leading the Team: Managing and guiding the team through planning, development, and release cycles.

Feature Planning and Release: Coordinating the planning and successful launch of new application features in alignment with project goals.

Projects:

Tips by Virtunus: 🗆

Responsibilities: Improved UI, added smooth animations, implemented a custom calendar, real-time report generator, multiple image upload, and the creation of the "Tips" feature (**uploading large JSON bodies**), along with ensuring support across multiple mobile devices.

Technologies Used: Flutter, custom animations, JSON.

Heal (Doctor Appointment System):

Overview: A platform designed to facilitate the process of finding reliable expert doctors and scheduling appointments.



Language

Java, Kotlin, XML, Dart, Basic swift.

Framework

Flutter, SwiftUI, Jetpack Compose.

Database

MySql, SQLite, Realm, Hive, SharedPrefernce.

Library

HILT, WebRTC, Sockert.io, Agora, Bloc, Provider, Freezed, GetIt, Riverpod, CachingManager, Dio, RxDart, Google Map, Animation, Firebase, Unit Test, WidgetTest.

Tools

Android Studio, Git, Postman, Jira, Xcode, AppCenter.

Paradigms

Scrum, Agile Software Development.



- Google Certified Associate Android Developer ☑
- The Complete 2021 Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart ☑
- Android Jetpack masterclass in Kotlin 🛭

Responsibilities: I was responsible for requirement analysis, design, and development of the mobile apps, and also led the mobile team. My work included application base architecture design using technologies such as **bloc**, dio, GetIt, **video/audio calls via Agora**, managing appointment details, integrating SSL payment gateway, scheduling today's appointments, and implementing dynamic linking.

Technologies Used: Flutter, **Agora, SSL**, dynamic linking. My work at Virtunus reflects a dedication to quality, innovation, and leadership, contributing to the successful delivery of diverse and complex projects.

ITECH Soft Solutions

Software Engineer(Mobile)

09/2020 - 09/2021 | Khulna, Bangladesh

Responsibilities/Tasks

My responsibility was to develop and maintain company products like ride-sharing, food delivery, and eCommerce flutter apps for Portugal clients.

[Projects] OkSofas ☑ : OKsofás products directly send users home, using our advanced augmented reality system.

Interspeed 🗆

Software Engineer(Mobile)

04/2018 - 09/2020 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities/Tasks

My responsibility was to develop and maintain company products like *Kotha* ☑ (Chatting and audio video calling, *Group Chat*, *Public Chat* app using

socket.io, **webrtc** and java), **JiggleMed** \square (USA based medical app).

W3 Engineers LTD

Android Developer

02/2016 - 03/2018 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities/Tasks

I worked on the Offline chat and content sharing application YO!, iDataShare(**Internet data sharing app**), Flare(Offline emergency help app using right mesh SDK).

REFERENCES

Ataul Mukit, CTO & Co-Founder, Kotha Apps & Technologies Ltd. ataul_mukit@hotmail.com, +8801819135815